<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>today-i-remember on slouch&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/tag/today-i-remember/</link>
    <description>Recent content in today-i-remember on slouch&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2023, slouch.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 08:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/tag/today-i-remember/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - cURL Impersonation</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-curl-impersonation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-curl-impersonation/</guid>
      <description>As a developer, linux user or command line fan, you might be familiar with the curl command. It is a powerful tool that allows you to transfer data from or to a server using various protocols, including HTTP, FTP, and SFTP. However, when testing websites, you may encounter issues where the server tries to fingerprint you using TLS, making it difficult to get the desired results.
Enter curl-impersonate1. It is an open-source tool that can be used as a drop-in replacement for the curl command, making it easier to bypass fingerprinting attempts and obtain the results you need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - JMP Chat SMS Service</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-jmp-chat-sms-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-jmp-chat-sms-service/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was curious about automating SMS. I really hate spam messages and wanted to distance my personal number from, well, not too privacy friendly services. While trialling digital SMS providers. I came across a myriad of issues. The issues almost always stem when receiving messages. The biggest issue of them all I found was receiving from short codes.
Short code numbers are the types of numbers you receive messages from when you get SMS/MMS marketing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Posting Schedule</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-posting-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-posting-schedule/</guid>
      <description>I have been producing tons of content recently, enthusiastic and remembering all of the things I can, wanting to share them with people on the internet. However, I started a little too excitedly!
Starting from next week, I am going to change the posting schedule. I will be posting content as much as I can, but realistically every Monday, Wednesday, and Friday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Python HTTP Requests Optimisation</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-python-http-requests-optimisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-python-http-requests-optimisation/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s world, speed is everything. When it comes to HTTP requests, faster is always better. Fortunately, there are many advanced methods to making faster HTTP requests in Python, including async requests, concurrent requests, and streaming options.
One of the most powerful options for faster HTTP requests is async requests. With async requests, you can send multiple requests simultaneously and wait for them all to return, rather than waiting for each request to complete before sending the next one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - AVDs on AWS</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-avds-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-avds-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>Recently I have been messing around with Android Virtual Devices (AVD). I realised, an issue when moving my tests to Amazon Web Services (AWS). The issue was with using Kernel-based Virtual Machine (KVM). Which does make sense from an infrastructure perspective for AWS. However, I still needed to resolve the issue.
KVM (Kernel-based Virtual Machine) is a widely used virtualization technology that enables the running of multiple virtual machines (VMs) on a single host machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Google Chrome Stable for ARM</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-google-chrome-stable-for-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-google-chrome-stable-for-arm/</guid>
      <description>Another short one today. A bit of a moan at that too&amp;hellip; Google Chrome is only packaged for amd64, and is not available for ARM on Linux systems. This is so frustrating!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - QRank Wikidata</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-qrank-wikidata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-qrank-wikidata/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across QRank1, which is an exciting project built on top of Wikidata that aims to provide a ranking signal for Wikidata entities. The QRank algorithm works by aggregating page view statistics for various Wikimedia projects, including Wikipedia, Wikitravel, Wikibooks, and Wikispecies. This data is then used to calculate a QRank score for each Wikidata entity, which can be used to assess the entity&amp;rsquo;s notability, popularity, and relevance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Almost Undetected Chromedriver</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-almost-undetected-chromedriver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-almost-undetected-chromedriver/</guid>
      <description>Web scraping has become an essential tool for data analysts, researchers, and even businesses. However, as websites have become smarter, web scraping has become more difficult. Many websites now implement tools such as CloudFlare to detect and block web scraping bots, which can make data collection a time-consuming and frustrating experience.
To help overcome these obstacles, developers have created various tools to make web scraping more effective. One such tool is the undetected-chromedriver1 library, which helps to speed up some necessary obfuscation work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Romance Scams</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-romance-scams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-romance-scams/</guid>
      <description>As an engineer, I keep on top of the most recent cybersecurity trends. Ensuring I do the most to keep myself, my customers and the internet secure. It is well known that humans tend to be the weakest link in the chain of security. With that in mind, you may have heard of cat-fishing. But do you know about the larger umbrella of romance scams?
Romance scams are a type of online fraud in which criminals create fake profiles on dating sites, social media platforms, or other online forums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Python Application Automation</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-python-application-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-python-application-automation/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in a previous blog, I have had some pretty strange edge-cases. Ones involving automating desktop applications. Before I mentioned using xdotool, but I have recently had to make a pure Python script to do something similar.
When it comes to pure Python desktop automation, PyAutoGUI has been a go-to solution for a while now. The Python library allows developers to automate their workflow by controlling the mouse and keyboard, taking screenshots, and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Deleted GoPro Footage</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-deleted-gopro-footage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-deleted-gopro-footage/</guid>
      <description>A short update today. I recently came across some old pictures and videos on my GoPro Session SD card that I thought I had lost. It turns out they were located in a hidden directory called .Trash-1000. It was a nice surprise to be able to reminisce and relive those memories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - E-mail Sign-up Trick</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-e-mail-sign-up-trick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-e-mail-sign-up-trick/</guid>
      <description>If you are looking for a simple but effective way to cut down on spam in your email inbox, you might want to try using the &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; operator in your email address. By appending a &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; symbol followed by a custom tag to your email address, you can create unique email addresses for each service or website you sign up for, while still receiving all emails in your main inbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Linux Desktop Automation</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-linux-desktop-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-linux-desktop-automation/</guid>
      <description>After receiving an edge-case in one of the systems I maintain. I had to come up with a pretty janky script to automate a Linux desktop application.
If you find yourself in the same situation, you might want to check out xdotool. This powerful tool offers a wide range of features for automating tasks such as window manipulation, keypress simulation, and more.
With just a few simple commands, you can automate a wide range of tasks, from opening and closing windows to simulating mouse clicks and keypresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - AWS DDK</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-aws-ddk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-aws-ddk/</guid>
      <description>If you are using Amazon Web Services (AWS) and looking for a powerful development kit to help you build and manage your data pipelines, you might want to check out the AWS DataOps Development Kit (DDK). Built on top of AWS&amp;rsquo;s popular Cloud Development Kit (CDK), the DDK is a powerful tool that offers a wide range of features for building and managing data pipelines in the cloud.
One of the key advantages of the DDK is its ease of use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Flask vs FastAPI</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-flask-vs-fastapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-flask-vs-fastapi/</guid>
      <description>Over the past couple of years people have asked a number of times why I keep choosing FastAPI over Flask. I should add a caveat that I am pretty much entirely Python based. So, when it comes to production ready APIs and such. FastAPI is my go-to.
Why FastAPI over Flask then? FastAPI is a modern, fast, and efficient framework that offers a wide range of features that make it an ideal choice for building high-performance web applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - The Cloud?!</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>After trying to convince management, that the cloud is the right choice for the majority of our architectures moving forwards. I found myself trying to summarise why it was important. Although this sounds like an advert (haha). This does go towards encapsulating some of the benefits of cloud native.
Are you looking for a way to make your workloads more efficient and cost-effective? If so, you might want to consider adopting a cloud-native approach to your computing infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Python Pydantic</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-python-pydantic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-python-pydantic/</guid>
      <description>Are you tired of dealing with the hassle of manual data validation in your Python code? If so, Pydantic might be the solution you are looking for. Pydantic is a data validation and settings management library that uses Python&amp;rsquo;s type annotations to define the shape of your data.
With Pydantic, you can define data models as standard Python classes with type annotations, making it easy to declare the types of your variables and get editor support for your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Python SQLite</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-python-sqlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-python-sqlite/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever needed to work with SQLite databases in Python? Perhaps you are dealing with a large dataset or building a web application that requires persistent storage. Whatever your use case, Python&amp;rsquo;s built-in sqlite3 module makes it easy to read, write, and manipulate SQLite databases.
To get started, you will first need to create a SQL connection to your SQLite database using the sqlite3.connect() method. This method takes the name of your SQLite database file as an argument and returns a connection object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Python Concurrency</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-python-concurrency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-python-concurrency/</guid>
      <description>Python is a powerful and versatile language, but there is one thing it is not so great at: multithreading. If you have ever tried to write a Python script that spawns multiple threads to do work in parallel, you may have run into issues with deadlocks, race conditions, or other concurrency bugs.
But fear not - there is a solution! The concurrent.futures module in Python 3 makes multithreading much more manageable, and can help you avoid many of the common pitfalls that come with concurrent programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - OOM-killer</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-oom-killer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-oom-killer/</guid>
      <description>If you are an experienced Linux user, you have probably encountered the dreaded oom-killer at some point. This is a feature of the kernel that kicks in when the system runs out of memory, killing processes to free up resources.
One common victim of the oom-killer is the sshd daemon, which can be a major problem if you rely on SSH for remote access to your server. But fear not - there is a solution!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Remember - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.slouch.dev/blog/today-i-remember-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Today I Learned [or Remembered]!
As an engineer with nearly a decade of experience in the industry. I have learned a lot over the years. Every day brings new challenges and opportunities to grow, and I am always striving to improve my skills and knowledge.
But I have also realized that with so much information to absorb, it is easy to forget some of the important lessons I have learned along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
